<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CTF on Drayko Escobar Blog</title>
    <link>https://drayko.github.io/tags/ctf/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CTF on Drayko Escobar Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Drayko Escobar</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://drayko.github.io/tags/ctf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>WriteUp CTF CIDSI 2018</title>
      <link>https://drayko.github.io/post/writeup-cidsi18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drayko.github.io/post/writeup-cidsi18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This CTF was composed of 74 teams from universities convened nationally for undergraduate and graduate level at the International Congress Of Computer Security (CIDSI in Spanish) which was organized by the Agency of Electronic Government and Information and Communication Technologies (AGETIC in Spanish). Thanks to the efforts of the Computer Incident Management Center(CGII) held from November 29 to December 1, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write Up CTF UMSS 2018</title>
      <link>https://drayko.github.io/post/writeup-ctfumss18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drayko.github.io/post/writeup-ctfumss18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the second part of the series of CTFs heading to CIDSI 2018. This time the CTF was held at the Universidad Mayor de San Simón (UMSS), a way of qualifying for those who would go to the event (CIDSI) representing our university.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write-Up: CIDSI 2018 Demo CTF</title>
      <link>https://drayko.github.io/post/writeup-democidsi18/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://drayko.github.io/post/writeup-democidsi18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hey there!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This is the first post in a series covering CTF challenges held during the International Congress on Information Security (CIDSI), organized by the Agency for Electronic Government and Information and Communication Technologies (AGETIC), thanks to the efforts of the Cyber Incident Management Center (CGII). The event took place from November 29 to December 1, 2018.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll start with the demo CTF challenge organized by CGII.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Submit the flag&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
